sapiens.org 2019-04-12

# Privacy Policy - SAPIENS

Last modified: 25 May 2018

**INTRODUCTION**

This privacy policy (“Privacy Policy”) applies to the personal information we collect about you through the website operated and made available by the Wenner-Gren Foundation for Anthropological Research, Incorporated (“Wenner-Gren,” “we,” “us,” and “our”) located at [www.wennergren.org](http://www.wennergren.org/) and any other websites under our control, including the website for the online publication SAPIENS located at www.sapiens.org (collectively, the “Websites”). This Privacy Policy applies regardless of media platform (e.g., computer, smartphone, tablet, etc.) used to access our Websites.

Your privacy is important to us, and this Privacy Policy is designed to make clear our intentions and approach to the collection and use of personal information in connection with our Websites and the choices you have.

Please contact us at [inquiries@wennergren.org](mailto:inquiries@wennergren.org) if:

  * You have any questions about this Privacy Policy
  * You would like to review, update, correct or delete personal information we have collected about you
  * If you would like to change any of your choices about personal information we collect about you
  * You would like to receive your personal data in a machine-readable format and send it to another controller

**YOUR CONSENT; OPTING-OUT**

By using the Websites, you agree to the terms of this Privacy Policy. If you do not agree with the terms of this Privacy Policy, please refrain from using the Websites. Specifically, by using our websites and submitting any  **Personal Information**  (as defined below in “Information We Collect & How We Collect It”) to us, you consent and agree that we may collect, use, and disclose that information (including information which may be personally identifiable) in accordance with this Privacy Policy, and as permitted or required by law. You have the option of refraining from submitting  **Personal Information**  and reviewing, updating, correcting and deleting  **Personal Information**  you have submitted (by contacting us at [inquiries@wennergren.org](mailto:inquiries@wennergren.org)), and can limit your use of the Websites to those aspects that do not require  **Personal Information**  if you do not agree with our practices outlined in this Privacy Policy regarding  **Personal Information**. You can also request that we refrain from using **Personal Information** for certain uses described in this Privacy Policy (by contacting us a [inquiries@wennergren.org](mailto:inquiries@wennergren.org)). You can also opt-out of our collection of **Website User Information** by refraining from visiting our website or rejecting or deleting cookies (see Website User Information & Cookies/Web Beacons/Tracking below).    

**INFORMATION WE COLLECT & HOW WE COLLECT IT**

For the purposes of operating, improving, and monitoring the user experience on our Websites and our operations generally, we collect various information from those using the Websites. This information is broadly of two types: (1)  **Personal Information**  (information which is personal to you and can be used to identify you, such as your name and email address) and (2)  **Website User Information**  (such as the number of users—but not their names—who have viewed an article; in some jurisdictions, some of this Website User Information, such as IP address, may be deemed to be personal information) **.**

Website User Information & Cookies/Web Beacons/Tracking

When you access our Websites, we may collect  **Website User Information**  including, but not limited to, pages visited, hyperlinks used, type of device used, date, and time spent on our Websites.

Collecting such  **Website User Information**  may involve logging the IP address, operating system and browser software used by individual site visitors. From such information a user’s Internet Service Provider and other data could be inferred, but cannot be used to personally identify you. We use this information to understand how to service users of our Websites and improve our Websites and programs by using Google Analytics or other website analysis tools.

We may also use cookies, flash cookies, web beacons, tags, and/or other technologies to store and help track information about you to provide you with a customized and personal service. Most browsers are initially set to accept such technologies and offer easy instructions on setting your browser to reject some or all of them. For example, you may choose to delete cookies at any time. However, please note that various personalized functions and benefits of the Websites may not work properly if you reject our cookies or other web technologies.

We do not track visitors across third party websites to provide targeted advertising, and therefore do not respond to Do Not Track (DNT) signals.

Personal Information

You can access content on our Websites and use most features of our Websites without revealing any  **Personal Information.** We only collect  **Personal Information**  when you provide it to us directly (or as noted in the Website User Information), for example:

  * When you register for an account on the Websites to submit a grant application or otherwise;
  * If you register with us to receive email newsletters or other communications from us;
  * If you contact us through the Websites;
  * When you participate in surveys;
  * When you participate with social media accounts operated by Wenner-Gren;
  * If you register for and participate in our programs, activities, initiatives, and events;
  * When you provide User Content (as defined in the [Terms and Conditions of Use](https://www.sapiens.org/terms-use/)) such as comments or written submissions to SAPIENS on any part of the Websites that permit it; and
  * When we need to verify your account information.

When you interact with any Wenner-Gren and SAPIENS page or account on a social media platform, such as Facebook, Twitter, Google+, LinkedIn, Tumblr, YouTube, or Pinterest (collectively, “Wenner-Gren Social Media”), or when you use your social media account or credentials to log into the Websites, we may also collect the  **Personal Information  **that you make available to us on that page or through that account. (Please note that when you use third party social media platforms, your use of those platforms is governed by their privacy policies and not this Privacy Policy.)

Collection of Personal Information by Third Party

The Websites use third party services to collect  **Personal Information**  for certain activities, such as its online grant application, managing email communications, and posting user comments. Use of  **Personal Information**  is controlled both by this Privacy Policy and the privacy policies and practices of those third party service providers. If we are using a third party service to collect  **Personal Information  **in connection with a feature we offer on our Websites, we will provide you with a link to the service provider’s privacy policy.

**HOW WE USE PERSONAL INFORMATION WE COLLECT**

We use  **Personal Information** collected in ways that are compatible with the purposes for which it was intended to use.Specifically, we use personal information in any of the following ways:

  * To indicate that you are the author of User Content (as defined in our [Terms and Conditions of Use](http://sapiens.org/terms-use/)) if you submit such content with your name;
  * To communicate with you periodically via email, if you have subscribed to one of our email lists;
  * To communicate with you in connection with processing your grant application or employment application;
  * To communicate with you about your account or any transactions with us;
  * To respond to you when you contact us. We may also archive this information and/or use it for future communications with you.
  * To contact you with service messages related to or affecting your use of our Websites, for example, to send you updates about changes in our terms or policies;
  * To send you marketing messages, special offers, promotions, and other information about us and our programs and services, and other products or services that we think may be of interest to you (see opt-out procedures in “Your Choices and Communications Preferences” below);
  * To facilitate your registration for an event or program;
  * To investigate any activities that may violate our policies or be illegal;
  * To manage and operate our Websites, and our organization in general.

We will retain your **Personal Information** for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with services ****

**DISCLOSURE OF PERSONAL INFORMATION**

Except as set forth in this Privacy Policy or as specifically agreed to by you, we will not disclose any  **Personal Information**  we gather from you through the Websites.

**Third Party Service Providers/Program Partners**. We might share  **Personal Information**  with trusted third-party vendors to help us in operating our Websites, programs and services. Also, if we work with a partner to help us to develop content and programs, we might share our email list and other information with them on a confidential basis.

**Legal and Governmental Authorities/Protection.**  To comply with legal requirements that may arise, we may share your  **Personal Information**  if requested to do so by legal or government authorities, or to protect our rights and property under the law. Such uses include, but are not restricted to: responding to court orders or subpoenas, to establish or exercise our legal rights or defend against legal claims and attacks on our reputation, to protect our property, including intellectual property and trademarks, or to enforce this Privacy Policy or our Terms and Conditions of Use. In such cases we reserve the right to raise or waive any legal objection or right available to us. We also may share your  **Personal Information**  when necessary to investigate, prevent, or take action regarding illegal or suspected illegal activities and to protect and defend the rights, property, or safety of Wenner-Gren and its staff, its properties, users of our Websites, or others.

**Disclosure to Acquirers.**  We may disclose and/or transfer your  **Personal Information**  to an acquirer, assignee or other successor or potential successor entity in connection with a merger, acquisition or other reorganization, provided that party agrees to treat your  **Personal Information**  with protections similar to those under this Privacy Policy. If we intend to share your Personal Information with an acquirer, we will notify you and give you the option to opt-out.   

**User Content.  **Your name or username will appear next to any User Content you submit to us. If you post  **Personal Information**  in comments or other public forums on our Websites or on Wenner-Gren Social Media, that information will be publicly available. If you are concerned about your privacy, we encourage you to use a username that is not personally identifiable and to refrain from posting  **Personal Information**  in comments or other public forums on our Websites or Wenner-Gren Social Media. You may delete your **Personal Information** in comments or other forums but we are not able to recall information which you have made public prior to such deletion. 

**Aggregated Data**. We may share  **Non-Personal Information**  in an aggregated form or publish information based on aggregated data. However, we will only do so in a way that your personal identity is protected.

Your Communications Preferences

You can elect to opt-out of subscription and marketing communications from us via the unsubscribe mechanism provided within the communications that you receive from us. Even if you unsubscribe from general email communications, we reserve the right to notify you of changes or updates to the Websites and to communicate with you about your user account(s) or User Content you have submitted as necessary.

**ACCESS, REVIEW, UPDATING, CORRECTING, AND DELETING PERSONAL INFORMATION**

You may review, update, correct or delete the  **Personal Information**  you have provided to us by contacting us at [inquiries@wennergren.org](mailto:inquiries@wennergren.org). Please note, however, that even if you delete your information, there may still be residual information about you in our systems, for example in our log files. Also, please note that we may retain certain  **Personal Information**  necessary to comply with our legal obligations, meet regulatory requirements, prevent fraud and abuse, or enforce our Terms and Conditions of Use. Upon request, we will also provide you with a copy of your personal data in a machine-readable format and send it to another data controller. You will need to provide sufficient identifying information, such as your name, email address and possibly additional information as security precaution in order to do any of the foregoing.

**DATA RETENTION**

We will retain your **Personal Information** for as long as your account is active or as needed to provide you with services. If you wish to cancel your account or request that we no longer use your **Personal Information** , to provide you with services, please contact us at [inquiries@wennergren.org](mailto:inquiries@wennergren.org). We will retain and use your information as necessary to comply with our legal obligations, resolve disputes, prevent fraud and abuse and enforce our policies and agreements.   

**YOUR RESPONSIBILITIES**

It is your responsibility to maintain the confidentiality of your password(s).

You are also responsible for ensuring the accuracy of the  **Personal Information**  you submit to us. Submitting inaccurate information, or failing to maintain the accuracy of information that changes (for example, a change of email address) may disrupt your ability to receive email communications, may affect the information you receive from us, and may impact our ability to contact you/and or process your grant application. You can update your  **Personal Information**  at any time by logging into your relevant user accounts with us and our third party service providers. If you have any questions about updating your  **Personal Information** , please contact us at [inquiries@wennergren.org](mailto:inquiries@wennergren.org).

**EXTERNAL LINKS**

We may occasionally provide links to Websites operated by outside parties, including social media platforms (“Third Party Websites”), that we believe may be of interest to you. We do not disclose your  **Personal Information**  to these Third Party Websites without obtaining your consent. However, if you choose to interact with Third Party Websites from our Websites (such as by “liking” something on Facebook or sharing via a social media platform), then your activities will not be governed by this Privacy Policy but by the privacy policy on that Third Party Site. Please review their privacy policies and terms of service before disclosing any  **Personal Information**  there. We do not review and expressly do not endorse and are not responsible for the privacy practices of these Third Party Websites.

We may also maintain a page on Facebook or other Wenner-Gren Social Media (as defined in “Information We Collect and How We Collect It” above). Those pages and your interaction with them are governed by the privacy policies of Facebook or other relevant Wenner-Gren Social Media, not by our Privacy Policy. As with other Third Party Websites, we do not endorse and are not responsible for the privacy practices of social media platforms, although we may have a presence on them.

**SECURITY**

We are committed to protecting the security of our users’  **Personal Information**. To that end, we use industry standard security practices to keep your  **Personal Information**  private, and to protect it from disclosure to or access by third parties. We will not share it with third parties, except as directed by you or as otherwise specified in this Privacy Policy. Please note, however, that we do not and cannot guarantee the security of  **Personal Information** , and there is some risk that an unauthorized third party may find a way to circumvent our security systems, or that transmission of your information over the Internet will be intercepted. We disclaim all liability involving  **Personal Information**  submitted through our Websites.

**CHANGING OUR PRIVACY POLICY**

We review our privacy practices from time to time, and these practices are subject to changes and updates. We will notify you of any material change to this Privacy Policy by reflecting the change on this Privacy Policy page, and by updating the Effective Date located at the top of this page. If the change affects how we collect, use or disclose **Personal Information** , we will notify you by email. To ensure familiarity with the current version of our Privacy Policy, return to this page periodically. We will not apply any changes retroactively and you have the option to opt-out of further collection of **Personal Information** and deletion of any existing **Personal Information**.

**PROTECTING CHILDREN’S PRIVACY**

We strongly believe in protecting the privacy of children. We do not knowingly collect or maintain any  **Personal Information**  on our Websites from persons under 13 years of age, and no part of our Websites are directed to persons under 13 years of age. Upon learning of the existence of  **Personal Information**  concerning persons less than 13 years of age that has been collected on our Websites without verified parental consent, we will take appropriate steps to delete it.

**GOVERNING LAW; INTERNATIONAL USERS**

This Privacy Policy shall be governed by the laws of the State of New York (United States), excluding any laws that might direct the application of the laws of another jurisdiction. Note that we may store and process  **Personal Information**  on servers or on a cloud located in the United States or elsewhere. The data protection laws of New York and the United States generally may not be as comprehensive or the same as those in the country where you are located. By using our Websites, you agree and consent that your  **Personal Information**  may be transferred to or stored in facilities in the United States or elsewhere.

[A Note to European Users: Regardless of where we store and process data, we take steps to protect your information, consistent with the principles set forth in this Privacy Policy, which are [intended to comply with the Privacy Shield Framework](https://orcid.org/sites/default/files/ckfinder/userfiles/files/2018_ORCID%2520Privacy%2520Shield%2520Certification.pdf) issued by the U.S. Department of Commerce . As a nonprofit organization, we are not subject to the jurisdiction of the United State Federal Trade Commission, which oversees the implementation of the Privacy Shield program. Consequently, we cannot self-certify compliance.]

**QUESTIONS OR CONCERNS**

If you have any trouble logging in, or have any privacy-related questions or unresolved problems, please contact us at [inquiries@wennergren.org](mailto:inquiries@wennergren.org).
